# Emi Katsuta

914-310-2573 | emi.katsuta@gmail.com | Github: @ekatsuta | Blog: https://medium.com/@emi.katsuta | LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/emi-katsuta

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software engineer committed to creating beautiful websites and intuitive user interfaces. Experience in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux and CSS. Enjoys the mix of logic and creativity in coding. Fluent in Japanese and French. Background in fashion merchandising.

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Nido - Github Backend | Github Frontend

A web app to connect volunteers offering up housing with caseworkers representing refugees & asylum seekers

- Built React app with double authentication & authorization between hosts and caseworkers
- Leveraged Redux to enhance the readability and efficiency of the React components
- Built a Ruby on Rails API to store information on the users, home listings and cases

## SKINN - Github Backend | Github Frontend

A React application to select and curate natural beauty regimens

- Built React app with Bcrypt authentication & client-side routes using react-router
- Configured ActiveRecord associations with Postgres to store data on users & beauty products
- Constructed custom algorithm to generate suggested products based on the user's skin type

## Ellis - Github Backend | Github Frontend

A Vanilla Javascript U.S. citizenship test flash card application

- Built using JavaScript with interactive UI such as event on scroll and card flip
- Used Chartis to visualize the user's past test score analysis & current session data
- Created Ruby on Rails API to store information on users' past scores

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, SQL, PostgreSQL, Git, HTML, CSS

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Hermes of Paris – New York, NY; Sr. Merchandise Manager, Men's Universe & Equestrian – Sept 2016 - Apr 2019

Merchandise Manager, Home & Tableware – Sept 2014 - Sept 2016

Merchandise Coordinator – Oct 2013 - Aug 2014

- Organized and presented state of current business and communicated successes, challenges, & strategies to Management and Paris HQ
- Developed and executed merchandising strategies leading to improved sell-through & Y/Y growth in designated departments
- Provided detailed sales analysis and align collection buys with global strategy to assist Store Directors during market
- Designed monthly sales reports by store by product category for comprehensive sales, inventory and forecasting analysis purposes
- Worked cross-functionally with Visual Merchandising, PR, and Communications teams on store events and product launches
- Managed Equestrian Account Executive and the merchandising internship program, and developed their critical thinking skills

## Comptoir des Cotonniers – New York, NY; Retail Merchandising/Operations Assistant; June 2011 – Oct 2013

- Analyze business in the U.S. region and share daily sales flash to Paris headquarters.
- Organize press day and special events, handle social media, coordinate U.S. PMO, newsletters and product knowledge seminars.
- Translate (French to English) operation documents, marketing tools and other materials sent from Paris.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School-**NY, NY *Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program;* August 2019 **Hamilton College-**Clinton, NY *Bachelor of Arts, French Language and Studio Arts;* May 2011 Major GPA: 3.9

## **INTERESTS**

Illustration, Graphic Design, Classical Piano, Running, Yoga, Hip Hop Dance